Matthias Mullie

Full-stack developer

Liisterstraat 7 8550 Zwevegem, BE +32 472 42 89 94 matthias@mullie.eu

www.mullie.eu github.com/matthiasmullie stackoverflow.com/users/802993 twitter.com/matthiasmullie

I'm a senior software engineer with an appetite for complex problems. I'm easy going & take responsibility for my work. Most of my expertise is with PHP, Python, MySQL, JavaScript & related tech.

I care about code architecture. I love hard challenges, clean code & learning new things. Bonus points for open source projects. I play soccer & like to travel.

Experience

B 4 (*)		•	- 1	
Wı	kimed	lıa.	Found	lation

San Francisco, USA (remote)

2012 - present

Software engineer

Helped build (cross-wiki) notifications & discussion board. Focused on:

- performance & scaling (e.g. reduced board load time by 3/4)
- storage & architecture (e.g. built transactional cache layer)
- new features like (elastic) search, import/export, permissions (auch!), config, spam/abuse prevention, ...

Wijs

Ghent, BE, 2008 - 2012

Lead developer

I lead our client projects and (tried to) make sure they shipped flawlessly. Grew Fork CMS to 4k+ installs/month & lead its technical direction. Built theming, i18n, search, module & theme installers, ...

Web developer

Kuurne, BE, 2008

Blade fx

I sliced up designs & implemented the websites with the company's proprietary ASP framework.

Own (open source) projects

Cauditor.org

PHP code analyzer

Set up this AWS-hosted SaaS to extract/visualize metrics for PHP projects. Link GitHub repos & send to 2 SQS queues (1 priority for last commit, other for history) where metrics are generated and submitted back to website. Site is Python, analyzer is PHP (and open source)

Scrapbook.cash Transactional cache I implemented a Memcached-like API for multiple cache backends, with stampede protection & transactions(!) etc. on top.

Minifier.org JS & CSS minifier

How did a few regular expressions for a CMS grow into this thing with 100k+ installs? I'm still convinced these regexes beat an AST approach!

Education

Katho

Kortrijk, BE, 2004 - 2011

Bachelor in Applied Computer Science

VDAB

Wevelgem, BE, 2007 - 2008

PHP developer

Sint-Amandscollege

Kortrijk, BE, 2002 - 2004

IT Management

Spes Nostra Institute

Heule, BE, 1998 - 2002

Latin-Math